## yes yes yeah okay would you take the position
## that you just took with any other injustice
## let's say you're the victims in this scenario
## would you find it acceptable for your oppressor
## to try to harm you less and to do less harming
## of you or would you want them to stop entirely
## immediately so please don't compromise
## when it comes to these non-human animals
## because they suffer just like you would if you
## were in their position again they may not like
## the sound of that um that it may not be what they
## want to hear because essentially what they're
## doing when they say i'm going to try or reduce
## is they're pandering to you because they want
## to tell you what you want to hear they can see
## that they're in they're on the wrong side of this
## that's why they're saying these things to
## you to end the conversation you you become a
## mirror at that point for the ugliness that they
## represent and when you say that their stance is
## not acceptable regardless of what they say after
## that you've put the needle where it needs to be
## an effective statement in this situation can be
## and this is the last line that we always give
## people we tend to leave them with this so keep in
## mind that for however long that you're not vegan
## animals will be abused and tortured because of you
## so when you're ready to stop abusing animals and
## align your actions with your words you know what
## to do think about what side of history you want to
## stand on what i'd leave you guys with is just keep
## in mind that for however long you're not vegan
## unfortunately you guys are going to be
## responsible for what's taking place on
## the screen this animal abuse so just think
## about and decide what side of history you
## guys want to stand on when it comes to stamping
## out this injustice and that's the workshop guys