## non-vegans aren't merely doing that non-vegans
## are quite literally responsible for the shooting
## for the enslavement for the torture and the
## murder so contribution and support are not
## accurate words to be using here responsibility
## is the word to replace those words in all cases
## tie in the benefit tie into benefit
## only once they concede by saying
## if they're against animal abuse
## then it's not possible to be against
## animal abuse while being responsible for
## it the number one benefit for being vegan
## the benefit is that they no longer have
## to be tortured and abused because of you
## in other words you no longer have to be the reason
## that animals suffer in the worst unimaginable ways
## for you as an individual if you say
## that you're against animal abuse
## and what you see on the screens then when you're
## vegan you no longer have to be a hypocrite
## now this is the part of the
## interaction where things get very real
## and where the person understands that you're not
## just having a wishy-washy you're not just verbally
## leafleting you're not just saying what vegans
## tend to say you're having a real conversation
## about a real issue here and you're calling
## them out but you're not doing it because you
## are trying to be an [ __ ] you also should
## understand that telling somebody the truth is
## the most compassionate thing that you can do it's
## the most kind and loving thing that you can do
## sometimes the truth can be harsh and can
## sound brutal but you have to understand
## that that's just the nature of truth the
## truth is not always a bowl of cherries
## and when you're a medium of truth you have
## to accept that as part of your responsibility
## when you're spreading the truth you have to
## be comfortable with the fact that sometimes
## it will sound brutal but you're not saying
## it from a malicious place your intention
## is to end animal abuse and to change the actions
## of humans so that they are no longer responsible
## for it in a way it's liberating for the human as
## well as the animal who they are responsible for
## oppressing so do you know what the number one
## benefit is for being vegan can you take a guess
## yeah what do you think it is that as well yeah
## yeah maybe it will help um like the industry
## to not like produce as much yeah because you're
## no longer demanding yeah and they are supplying
## demand that's basic economics you're one less
## person who's demanding it yeah let me put it
## to you this way also the number one benefit for
## the animals is that they're no longer tormented
## abused and harmed in any way because of you
## you're no longer the reason that animals
## suffer immensely are tormented and murdered
## the benefit for you as individuals also
## is that when you say you're against animal
## abuse you'll no longer be hypocrites
## do you disagree with that does that does that
## sound fair to you does that make sense to you
## yeah this drives home the accountability and makes
## them understand the consequences of their choices
## so this is where you close the conversation always
## end every outreach conversation by asking what the
## individual will be personally doing to
## take action ask the open-ended question
## after our conversation what are you
## going to do about this injustice
## after a long conversation they may they may
## still say that they'll only reduce or do nothing
## or they may say something like i'll try to do
## better if you can sense that the interaction will
## keep going in circles end the conversation with
## the statement but with people who say i'm going
## to try to do better or i'll reduce how much meat i
## eat they are still not getting how serious this is
## do you deem this to be an injustice
## and usually they will say yes i do
## and then i say would you take the stance that you
## just took with any other injustice you know if we
## were talking about yourself as the victim in this
## injustice would you find it acceptable for your
## oppressor to say that they are going to try to
## stop oppressing you or would you only deem it
## acceptable for them to stop immediately so
## what do you think you'll do about this then
## eat less medium yeah maybe even stop eventually
## okay now is what you're seeing on the screens
## is animal abuse and injustice to each of you