## reason but what they're usually doing is they're
## trying to deflect from accountability they're
## trying to distract the conversation
## so that they don't have to take action
## so you have to understand that before
## you entertain any of those points this
## is another reason why you shouldn't bring
## up health and environment talking points
## and this is something i've learned time and time
## again when i do bring up health and environment
## if i entertain those points and i know that
## sometimes it can be tempting super tempting
## you will end up debating how much iron you
## get as a vegan or whatever the case may be
## all of it is just a distraction to
## what really needs to be discussed
## not everybody on the streets is worth talking to
## part of your role is to assess who is reachable
## and who is not many people are not reachable this
## is a numbers game i've had cubes where i've had
## zero people take the issue seriously over the
## course of three or four hours as part for the
## course i've had cubes where almost every person
## i spoke to was open and willing and they got it
## plenty of those people that are open and worth
## talking to are out there i also will say that
## even if somebody doesn't get it and you've
## said the correct thing on behalf of the animals
## it is still worthwhile because you
## never know what kind of an effect
## what you've said will have
## on that person's subconscious
## and you never know how that may come up again
## within them in future if they want to have a
## short conversation with you keep it short with
## them don't entertain bystanders who want to engage
## in long argumentative debates do not underestimate
## the cunningness of non-vegan guilt and the ability
## that many non-vegans will have to waste your vital
## time at work for the animals if people don't take
## this issue seriously expect that they will want
## to waste your time they may even seem sincere
## and nice they may seem like very sweet people but
## if they don't take this issue seriously they may
## just take you for a ride and waste your time when
## people feel guilty and most people you speak with
## by and large will feel guilty
## when their guilt flares up
## they will have all of these mechanisms that come
## up to protect themselves or to defend themselves
## and to justify their guilt and that's what
## we mean by the cunningness of non-vegan guilt
## you shouldn't underestimate it you should
## understand that it's a very real thing
## and it will cause humans to behave in
## very irrational ways i've never seen
## people act more irrationally that i have with
## non-vegans when we address this issue with them
## so again activism is not sales sales training does
## not equal good activism using slick talk to trick
## people into veganism does not work your job is
## to hold the bystander accountable it's up to
## them which actions they take initially av made too
## strong of a connection between sales and activism
## tools taught in sales training only go so far
## so this is why i'm making such a strong point
## about the sales stuff it's because back in 2016
## when we put together the model for the cube of
## truth and the outreach element to the cube i did
## actually make too strong of a connection between
## sales and activism so this was back in 2016 that
## i did this and i essentially called what i was
## bringing to the table a value-based sales approach
## and when i said a value-based sales approach i was
## intending on differentiating from the
## general regular form of sales that people
## are commonly used to value based meaning
## there is no money involved here however
## what this did is it created this idea that if
## you have 10 20 30 40 50 years of sales experience
## that you're automatically experienced as an
## activist and that's just not how this works at all
## in fact what i've found is and i've personally
## done sales for well over 10 years is a lot of what
## i learned is not actually applicable most of what
## i learned is not applicable in activism whatsoever
## in fact a lot of the little tools that we did
## bring over into activism we no longer really use
## it's just good to understand how certain aspects
## of sales work i just shared one thing with you
## guys which is kiss keep it simple stupid i'm
## not even sure if that belongs to the sales world