## when you're on the streets and people stop at
## a cube you know they're not usually looking
## for something that's too deep when they interact
## with you most people in terms of digesting this
## information will prefer for you to keep it simple
## and keep the statistics and the facts to a minimum
## if the goal were to provide information we would
## hand out leaflets and magazines and brochures the
## function of outreach is to make people understand
## the consequences of their choices by holding them
## accountable and centering the interaction about
## what they can personally do about animal abuse
## on an individual level most people you speak with
## will try to deflect from accountability and palm
## this off to governments or corporations and say
## that they need to change or they might even start
## talking about other human beings and say how are
## you going to get the whole world to become vegan
## though these kinds of distractions that they
## bring up are all to deflect from accountability
## individual accountability so it's your job as
## an activist to bring it back to the individual
## veganism is not about love or
## compassion you can dislike animals
## and you are still obligated to be vegan
## in the same way that it applies to humans
## you can hate people but you don't have the
## right to enslave torture and murder them
## veganism is about justice your likability
## does not determine your rights so outreach
## is not about how you or anyone else feels
## about animals necessarily if you don't go
## around beating children you aren't
## instantly a compassionate individual
## if you don't go around abusing animals on the
## streets you're not necessarily a compassionate
## person refraining from injustice does not make you
## compassionate by default veganism is a non-action
## therefore it's not loving it's merely the right
## thing to do the same and rational thing to do
## this approach that i'm teaching you is about pure
## honesty telling someone the truth is the most
## respectful thing that you can do for them when you
## agree with every statement said by the bystander
## they will often lose respect for you and
## you will lose control of the conversation
## when you do this they see that your desire
## to be validated by them is stronger than
## your desire to end animal cruelty and the
## whole reason why you're standing out on the
## streets trying to engage with the public
## thereby making a mockery of animal rights
## can you imagine if the primary goal of human
## rights activists was to be liked by the oppressors
## in any other context this would be insane
## you may be hesitant to speak boldly whenever you
## are afraid to speak up for the animals directly
## or if bystanders call you too extreme
## place yourself in the victims position
## and analyze your approach from their perspective
## could you look a cow in the eyes and say i'm doing
## my best on your behalf i'm speaking for you as
## if i was in your position would you consider a
## respectful yet direct conversation too extreme if
## you were locked up in a slaughterhouse right now
## don't talk about health and environment this
## is obviously a huge thing in the animal rights
## movement vegans so often talk about human
## health and the environment with an aim
## to hook people in to becoming vegan and we
## tell ourselves it doesn't matter how we get
## people to go vegan just as long as they go
## vegan the problem with this idea is that
## more often than not it's a myth that these
## people actually go vegan and if they do
## become plant-based what they end up doing is
## becoming the worst kind of candidate for a vegan
## because they are the type of vegans
## to rub veganism through the mud on
## the basis of doing it for their health or for
## the environment both of which are human-centric
## it's still a selfish message that you're
## promoting which is completely beside the point
## and not the basis for veganism the whole point
## of veganism is altruism doing something for
## non-human animals non-human animals deserve
## to have a cause dedicated to them and so