## but that's where i learned it and it
## applies to almost everything in life
## and in essence at its very basis sales applies
## to life you know if you have children and they
## love to eat confectionery every day for every
## meal convincing them to eat a carrot is sales
## i'm convincing you right now to take this
## approach seriously and to follow this protocol
## while you're at cubes of truth but my point is
## that it can get blown out of proportion and like
## i said it doesn't necessarily mean everything that
## you've learned in sales is applicable in activism
## a successful conversation is not one where the
## bystander says i'm going vegan it's where you say
## the right things this is really important
## again like i was saying before some people
## may not seem open and willing they may not
## give you the answer that you're looking for
## when people say i'm going vegan that's obviously a
## good indication but they may not be they may just
## be excited in the moment they may not be genuine
## about that the best way to measure whether you've
## had a good interaction is to look at what
## you've said have you said the correct thing
## on behalf of the animals or not if you have
## you've done the best that you can possibly do
## most people become vegan after they hear the truth
## from us how long it takes is up to the individual
## the socratic method just by show of hands how
## many of you don't know about the socratic method
## okay there's a few of you so socratic method
## it's named after socrates and essentially what he
## taught was when you're in a debate with somebody
## and this is more of a debate tactic so that's
## why it's not applicable in its entirety to an
## outreach conversation because the whole thing
## isn't necessarily a debate the whole thing is
## an interaction that will involve some parts of
## it being a debate and so what he taught was
## instead of framing something as a statement
## in this context for example animal cruelty is
## wrong right that's a statement the better way to
## frame it is as a question what do you think about
## animal cruelty do you think that animal cruelty
## is wrong or how do you feel about animal cruelty
## so one of those variations was a closed question
## and two of them was an open-ended question we'll
## get into the open-ended questions in this slide
## so credit questioning is a communication tool
## that we use within our approach it is not an
## approach in and of itself where we ask questions
## to lead the bystander to their own conclusions
## use open-ended questions such as why are you
## against animal abuse instead of a closed statement
## such as animal abuse is wrong open-ended questions
## are generally preferred to anchor and progress the
## conversation you should use closed-ended
## questions and statements also but usually
## an open-ended question does a better
## job sometimes you just need to seal
## off and confirm an aspect of what it is that
## you're discussing at that particular moment
## and that's where the closed-ended questions are
## important okay this is important you versus we
## we don't torture and kill animals for products
## non-vegans do using we undermines individual
## accountability this has been a personal lesson for
## me and something that we've all learned within av
## for quite some time now but essentially what we
## do as activists is we find ourselves saying we
## we with non-vegans all the time why do we do this
## to animals you know we grow up i know that we're
## trying to relate to non-vegans but it does take
## away from individual accountability and people do
## need to understand the clear difference between
## veganism and non-veganism and they will not see
## and understand that difference clearly enough
## if you keep using language that isn't accurately
## describing the issue if you keep saying we you're
## not actually being accurate so be careful about
## what it is you're saying when you tell non-vegans
## that we as a society are responsible for animal
## cruelty in farms it takes away the imperative
## for individual accountability it makes them
## think of lobbying or government programs instead
## of personal responsibilities people need to feel
## guilty to change they'll only change once they
## understand that there is a difference between you
## the vegan and them the non-vegan i understand that
## that last slide might seem like we are creating