## the outreach workshop that
## i'm doing for you guys is
## relevant to the cube of truth we
## are going to start right at the top
## so the first part of this workshop is about
## veganism because we have to get clear about what
## veganism actually means before we start talking
## about how to do outreach veganism if you ask a
## group of people what it means you'll get multiple
## versions of what they believe it to be you
## probably had this experience just by interacting
## with vegans you'll find that the definition that
## they hold dear to them is quite different for
## everybody veganism has nothing to do with our
## health it has nothing to do with the environment
## it has nothing to do with human rights it has
## nothing to do with our affection towards animals
## it is only about justice for non-human animals
## as far as it pertains to humans inflicting
## harm exploitation suffering etc upon non-human
## animals so this is about addressing non-human
## animal exploitation at the hands of humans
## in essence to summarize vegan
## equals anti-animal abuse
## activism what does it mean in essence what
## it means is speaking up for the victims in
## the same way that you would want to be
## spoken for if you were in their position
## it is being a medium of truth and enacting change
## by prioritizing the victims and not the oppressors
## i recently made a post on social media
## and the caption for that post summarizes
## in essence what we do on the streets
## and why we focus on what we focus on
## animal agriculture doesn't start with corporations
## it doesn't start with the government it doesn't
## even start with farms it starts with you it starts
## with the consumer the consumers who demand the
## products and there's many different ways that
## you can create demand for animal exploitation
## you may not necessarily purchase it may be given
## to you you may be wearing secondhand leather
## somebody might pay for your ticket to go to a zoo
## there's many other circumstances i could point out
## but you are creating demand and you're promoting
## that this culture of animal exploitation within
## humans is okay it's acceptable and that's
## what i mean by starting with us with humans
## and what we do on the streets is we focus on the
## demand we start from where it starts and it's not
## to say that it isn't important to work in the
## political sphere to end things like government
## subsidies for animal agriculture that is a worthy
## fight and i would like to see that succeed i would
## also like to see more of the direct action
## stuff that holds the corporations accountable
## but what we also really need is to start from
## where it starts which is the consumer demand so
## that's why we do what we do always remember
## that you will never have 100 success rate
## in animal rights outreach there is no magic
## set of words to use during outreach that
## will make someone go vegan if they're ready
## they'll listen if they're not ready they won't
## this is a very important point for you guys
## to understand because you might get down on
## yourself if you don't get through to somebody and
## you may think that you've said everything correct
## and you may have said it all correctly but at the
## end of the day it comes down to the individual
## whether they're willing and open to change
## and take action with the context provided your
## function as an activist is to hold the individual
## you're speaking with accountable for the animal
## abuse that they are responsible for and make
## them aware of the consequences of their choices
## your goal as an activist on the streets doing
## outreach at the cubes is not to plant seeds
## animal rights outreach is not verbal leafleting
## what we mean by that is you're not just riffing
## off information and factoids to people you're not
## literally a brochure in human form you're not just
## telling people about how old chickens are when
## they die how many chickens are killed you know
## etc um the whole point is you're actually
## interacting with somebody and you know there
## are certain facts and information that need to be
## used at certain points throughout the interaction
## but for the most part most people prefer things to
## be kept simple you might have heard the expression
## kiss keep it simple stupid it really does
## apply to the majority of the public especially