## division between us and individuals it's not about
## being deliberately combative and creating division
## with people it's again just about making sure that
## they understand clearly that there is a massive
## difference between veganism and non-veganism
## and i think you all already know this because
## otherwise you wouldn't be vegan and you wouldn't
## stay vegan and you understand that there is a
## big difference between what you're doing now and
## going back to being non-vegan a huge difference
## and that's why we should really be careful
## about the language we use okay why versus how
## people already know how to go vegan it's really
## simple stuff with the constant availability of
## google and the internet anybody can figure out
## how to become vegan instantly in order for people
## to feel the need to become vegan they need to
## be held accountable for why they should do it
## with any other injustice you would never focus
## on how by talking about how to not participate
## in the violence focusing on the how in the context
## of any other injustice would be an insult to the
## victims and the entire movement fighting to
## end their oppression part of me it's not to
## say that how is not an important talking point we
## should give people that but it's only at the very
## end once we have sufficiently and emphatically
## address the why factor you know we give people
## a card as you know at the end we always arm
## people with the resources and the how factor
## all you really need as a compass to be vegan is
## is what i'm doing right now vegan or not does this
## restaurant have vegan meals is this product vegan
## is this ingredient vegan is going to zoos vegan
## okay so it's really simple really really simple
## stuff and i think that you should be aware of
## whether you're coddling people into this or
## not and babying people into this is a problem
## it shows weakness in the actual
## message if you're doing that
## vegetarianism is cancer to animal rights i'm not
## just saying this for shock value i truly mean this
## the longer the vegetarianism and veganism
## get conflated the longer it will take
## for us to get the message out there that
## veganism is about non-human animal rights
## and that that is a serious injustice that
## people need to take very very seriously
## vegetarians are non-vegans and should be
## outreached in the same manner as anyone else
## and in most cases even harder vegetarians are our
## target market they're no different to paleo eaters
## people who eat a paleo diet why should we treat
## them any differently so as you may know people who
## eat a paleo diet do not eat dairy and we as vegans
## i use this point a lot and i hear other vegans
## using this point a lot we talk about how the
## dairy industry is quite possibly the cruelest
## industry at least for land animals on earth
## paleo eaters don't consume any dairy products
## why are they any different to
## vegetarians vegetarians don't consume
## flesh while flesh is an obvious form of cruelty
## we know as vegans that dairy is no different
## and that what happens on dairy farms and in
## slaughterhouses to the cows and their babies
## is nothing short of an atrocity of a holocaust
## and is no different to what happens to animals
## in the meat industry arguably it's worse than
## the dairy industry and so as you can imagine it
## would be insane for us to call paleo people our
## allies to put them in the same bracket as vegans
## so why are we doing this with vegetarians it
## makes absolutely no sense it's counterproductive
## and it absolutely will marginalize the
## seriousness of this injustice the longer
## that we make vegetarians feel like they are animal
## people like they are defenders of animals like
## they are on the side of animal rights they need
## to be held to account just like everybody else
## okay so they are not allies don't let other vegans
## or non-vegans manipulate you into thinking that
## they are so when you start the conversation you
## could say would you like to know why we're here
## what's up guys how you doing man i'm doing really
## well you wanna hear what we're doing oh sure