the outreach workshop that
i'm doing for you guys is
relevant to the cube of truth we
are going to start right at the top
so the first part of this workshop is about
veganism because we have to get clear about what
veganism actually means before we start talking
about how to do outreach veganism if you ask a
group of people what it means you'll get multiple
versions of what they believe it to be you
probably had this experience just by interacting
with vegans you'll find that the definition that
they hold dear to them is quite different for
everybody veganism has nothing to do with our
health it has nothing to do with the environment
it has nothing to do with human rights it has
nothing to do with our affection towards animals
it is only about justice for non-human animals
as far as it pertains to humans inflicting
harm exploitation suffering etc upon non-human
animals so this is about addressing non-human
animal exploitation at the hands of humans
in essence to summarize vegan
equals anti-animal abuse
activism what does it mean in essence what
it means is speaking up for the victims in
the same way that you would want to be
spoken for if you were in their position
it is being a medium of truth and enacting change
by prioritizing the victims and not the oppressors
i recently made a post on social media
and the caption for that post summarizes
in essence what we do on the streets
and why we focus on what we focus on
animal agriculture doesn't start with corporations
it doesn't start with the government it doesn't
even start with farms it starts with you it starts
with the consumer the consumers who demand the
products and there's many different ways that
you can create demand for animal exploitation
you may not necessarily purchase it may be given
to you you may be wearing secondhand leather
somebody might pay for your ticket to go to a zoo
there's many other circumstances i could point out
but you are creating demand and you're promoting
that this culture of animal exploitation within
humans is okay it's acceptable and that's
what i mean by starting with us with humans
and what we do on the streets is we focus on the
demand we start from where it starts and it's not
to say that it isn't important to work in the
political sphere to end things like government
subsidies for animal agriculture that is a worthy
fight and i would like to see that succeed i would
also like to see more of the direct action
stuff that holds the corporations accountable
but what we also really need is to start from
where it starts which is the consumer demand so
that's why we do what we do always remember
that you will never have 100 success rate
in animal rights outreach there is no magic
set of words to use during outreach that
will make someone go vegan if they're ready
they'll listen if they're not ready they won't
this is a very important point for you guys
to understand because you might get down on
yourself if you don't get through to somebody and
you may think that you've said everything correct
and you may have said it all correctly but at the
end of the day it comes down to the individual
whether they're willing and open to change
and take action with the context provided your
function as an activist is to hold the individual
you're speaking with accountable for the animal
abuse that they are responsible for and make
them aware of the consequences of their choices
your goal as an activist on the streets doing
outreach at the cubes is not to plant seeds
animal rights outreach is not verbal leafleting
what we mean by that is you're not just riffing
off information and factoids to people you're not
literally a brochure in human form you're not just
telling people about how old chickens are when
they die how many chickens are killed you know
etc um the whole point is you're actually
interacting with somebody and you know there
are certain facts and information that need to be
used at certain points throughout the interaction
but for the most part most people prefer things to
be kept simple you might have heard the expression
kiss keep it simple stupid it really does
apply to the majority of the public especially
when you're on the streets and people stop at
a cube you know they're not usually looking
for something that's too deep when they interact
with you most people in terms of digesting this
information will prefer for you to keep it simple
and keep the statistics and the facts to a minimum
if the goal were to provide information we would
hand out leaflets and magazines and brochures the
function of outreach is to make people understand
the consequences of their choices by holding them
accountable and centering the interaction about
what they can personally do about animal abuse
on an individual level most people you speak with
will try to deflect from accountability and palm
this off to governments or corporations and say
that they need to change or they might even start
talking about other human beings and say how are
you going to get the whole world to become vegan
though these kinds of distractions that they
bring up are all to deflect from accountability
individual accountability so it's your job as
an activist to bring it back to the individual
veganism is not about love or
compassion you can dislike animals
and you are still obligated to be vegan
in the same way that it applies to humans
you can hate people but you don't have the
right to enslave torture and murder them
veganism is about justice your likability
does not determine your rights so outreach
is not about how you or anyone else feels
about animals necessarily if you don't go
around beating children you aren't
instantly a compassionate individual
if you don't go around abusing animals on the
streets you're not necessarily a compassionate
person refraining from injustice does not make you
compassionate by default veganism is a non-action
therefore it's not loving it's merely the right
thing to do the same and rational thing to do
this approach that i'm teaching you is about pure
honesty telling someone the truth is the most
respectful thing that you can do for them when you
agree with every statement said by the bystander
they will often lose respect for you and
you will lose control of the conversation
when you do this they see that your desire
to be validated by them is stronger than
your desire to end animal cruelty and the
whole reason why you're standing out on the
streets trying to engage with the public
thereby making a mockery of animal rights
can you imagine if the primary goal of human
rights activists was to be liked by the oppressors
in any other context this would be insane
you may be hesitant to speak boldly whenever you
are afraid to speak up for the animals directly
or if bystanders call you too extreme
place yourself in the victims position
and analyze your approach from their perspective
could you look a cow in the eyes and say i'm doing
my best on your behalf i'm speaking for you as
if i was in your position would you consider a
respectful yet direct conversation too extreme if
you were locked up in a slaughterhouse right now
don't talk about health and environment this
is obviously a huge thing in the animal rights
movement vegans so often talk about human
health and the environment with an aim
to hook people in to becoming vegan and we
tell ourselves it doesn't matter how we get
people to go vegan just as long as they go
vegan the problem with this idea is that
more often than not it's a myth that these
people actually go vegan and if they do
become plant-based what they end up doing is
becoming the worst kind of candidate for a vegan
because they are the type of vegans
to rub veganism through the mud on
the basis of doing it for their health or for
the environment both of which are human-centric
it's still a selfish message that you're
promoting which is completely beside the point
and not the basis for veganism the whole point
of veganism is altruism doing something for
non-human animals non-human animals deserve
to have a cause dedicated to them and so
when we promote animal rights it should be about
animal rights why do we think people care about
either their health or the environment most people
in the streets do not care about their health
nor the environment so rooting out outreach
in these topics will marginalize the animals
health and environment have become exacerbated
because people do not take animal abuse
seriously trying to hook people with an approach
that revolves around what benefits them does a
disservice to the animals so focus on the
root cause of the issue the animal abuse
whenever people talk about how badly our
environment is affected by animal agriculture
whether it's someone who is vegan or non-vegan
talking about these points and by the way
most non-vegans already know about how bad
animal agriculture is for the environment why
do they know about this there are so many victims
involved in this injustice that it does in fact
impact the environment so the root cause of this
issue is animal abuse and so it makes no sense to
talk about the symptom and to make this again
a selfish message for humans to benefit from
why don't people care about ethics
because vegans don't advocate
for animals correctly
they focus on things like plant-based recipes
restaurants weight loss or deforestation another
reason is they lead with phrases like friends
not food or animal lovers don't eat animals
this is not a conversation about sympathy
this is a conversation about accountability
don't plead with bystanders make them
understand the consequences of their choices
by placing them in the victim's position morality
when it comes to this injustice and injustice in
general you can say but especially when it
comes to this injustice is black and white
if bystanders tell you that you aren't
considering the other side to this or that you
aren't open-minded enough that is a distraction
there is no other side to needless animal abuse
you either support it or you don't don't get lost
in these distractions compare animal abuse to a
comparable injustice and get it back on track when
you're comparing animal abuse to another injustice
we've found that the best thing to do is to
compare it to them put the bystander in that
cow's position how would you feel your babies
were being stolen from you after you were raped
and you had your neck sliced open what i found
is that most people mostly care about themselves
you know they're not really going to understand
unless they imagine for themselves what it would
be like if they were in that position if we want
them to connect to what animals are going through
which injustice should you compare to i just
touched on this a little bit but we'll get
further into it it is most effective to compare
the to injustices such as child abuse or human
trafficking but even better the most effective is
to place the bystander in the victim's position
avoid dog comparisons this goes back to not
leading with compassion it's not about the
love that people feel towards animals it's about
the hate that they feel towards injustice i can't
tell you how many times i've personally learned
this lesson about using dogs as a comparison
and people will say yeah well if i was in china i
would eat dogs here's the thing most people don't
view dogs truly as individuals one indication of
that in our society is that we have dog shelters
that kill dogs by the thousand and so again
most people mostly only care about themselves
it doesn't come down to whether you can
imagine your dog in a slaughterhouse
it comes down to whether you can
imagine yourself in a slaughterhouse
statistics keep them minimal outside of what is
asked of you state minimal information during
outreach conversations we are not on the streets
to verbally leaflet let the footage provide the
context to the conversation you aren't at a cube
of truth to be a statistician you're there to
have a concise conversation that holds people
to account for their unjustified animal abuse
a conversation will go on for longer than
necessary if it turns into an argument over
statistics and it's not to say that we can't
win these debates we can we have logic and facts
reason but what they're usually doing is they're
trying to deflect from accountability they're
trying to distract the conversation
so that they don't have to take action
so you have to understand that before
you entertain any of those points this
is another reason why you shouldn't bring
up health and environment talking points
and this is something i've learned time and time
again when i do bring up health and environment
if i entertain those points and i know that
sometimes it can be tempting super tempting
you will end up debating how much iron you
get as a vegan or whatever the case may be
all of it is just a distraction to
what really needs to be discussed
not everybody on the streets is worth talking to
part of your role is to assess who is reachable
and who is not many people are not reachable this
is a numbers game i've had cubes where i've had
zero people take the issue seriously over the
course of three or four hours as part for the
course i've had cubes where almost every person
i spoke to was open and willing and they got it
plenty of those people that are open and worth
talking to are out there i also will say that
even if somebody doesn't get it and you've
said the correct thing on behalf of the animals
it is still worthwhile because you
never know what kind of an effect
what you've said will have
on that person's subconscious
and you never know how that may come up again
within them in future if they want to have a
short conversation with you keep it short with
them don't entertain bystanders who want to engage
in long argumentative debates do not underestimate
the cunningness of non-vegan guilt and the ability
that many non-vegans will have to waste your vital
time at work for the animals if people don't take
this issue seriously expect that they will want
to waste your time they may even seem sincere
and nice they may seem like very sweet people but
if they don't take this issue seriously they may
just take you for a ride and waste your time when
people feel guilty and most people you speak with
by and large will feel guilty
when their guilt flares up
they will have all of these mechanisms that come
up to protect themselves or to defend themselves
and to justify their guilt and that's what
we mean by the cunningness of non-vegan guilt
you shouldn't underestimate it you should
understand that it's a very real thing
and it will cause humans to behave in
very irrational ways i've never seen
people act more irrationally that i have with
non-vegans when we address this issue with them
so again activism is not sales sales training does
not equal good activism using slick talk to trick
people into veganism does not work your job is
to hold the bystander accountable it's up to
them which actions they take initially av made too
strong of a connection between sales and activism
tools taught in sales training only go so far
so this is why i'm making such a strong point
about the sales stuff it's because back in 2016
when we put together the model for the cube of
truth and the outreach element to the cube i did
actually make too strong of a connection between
sales and activism so this was back in 2016 that
i did this and i essentially called what i was
bringing to the table a value-based sales approach
and when i said a value-based sales approach i was
intending on differentiating from the
general regular form of sales that people
are commonly used to value based meaning
there is no money involved here however
what this did is it created this idea that if
you have 10 20 30 40 50 years of sales experience
that you're automatically experienced as an
activist and that's just not how this works at all
in fact what i've found is and i've personally
done sales for well over 10 years is a lot of what
i learned is not actually applicable most of what
i learned is not applicable in activism whatsoever
in fact a lot of the little tools that we did
bring over into activism we no longer really use
it's just good to understand how certain aspects
of sales work i just shared one thing with you
guys which is kiss keep it simple stupid i'm
not even sure if that belongs to the sales world
but that's where i learned it and it
applies to almost everything in life
and in essence at its very basis sales applies
to life you know if you have children and they
love to eat confectionery every day for every
meal convincing them to eat a carrot is sales
i'm convincing you right now to take this
approach seriously and to follow this protocol
while you're at cubes of truth but my point is
that it can get blown out of proportion and like
i said it doesn't necessarily mean everything that
you've learned in sales is applicable in activism
a successful conversation is not one where the
bystander says i'm going vegan it's where you say
the right things this is really important
again like i was saying before some people
may not seem open and willing they may not
give you the answer that you're looking for
when people say i'm going vegan that's obviously a
good indication but they may not be they may just
be excited in the moment they may not be genuine
about that the best way to measure whether you've
had a good interaction is to look at what
you've said have you said the correct thing
on behalf of the animals or not if you have
you've done the best that you can possibly do
most people become vegan after they hear the truth
from us how long it takes is up to the individual
the socratic method just by show of hands how
many of you don't know about the socratic method
okay there's a few of you so socratic method
it's named after socrates and essentially what he
taught was when you're in a debate with somebody
and this is more of a debate tactic so that's
why it's not applicable in its entirety to an
outreach conversation because the whole thing
isn't necessarily a debate the whole thing is
an interaction that will involve some parts of
it being a debate and so what he taught was
instead of framing something as a statement
in this context for example animal cruelty is
wrong right that's a statement the better way to
frame it is as a question what do you think about
animal cruelty do you think that animal cruelty
is wrong or how do you feel about animal cruelty
so one of those variations was a closed question
and two of them was an open-ended question we'll
get into the open-ended questions in this slide
so credit questioning is a communication tool
that we use within our approach it is not an
approach in and of itself where we ask questions
to lead the bystander to their own conclusions
use open-ended questions such as why are you
against animal abuse instead of a closed statement
such as animal abuse is wrong open-ended questions
are generally preferred to anchor and progress the
conversation you should use closed-ended
questions and statements also but usually
an open-ended question does a better
job sometimes you just need to seal
off and confirm an aspect of what it is that
you're discussing at that particular moment
and that's where the closed-ended questions are
important okay this is important you versus we
we don't torture and kill animals for products
non-vegans do using we undermines individual
accountability this has been a personal lesson for
me and something that we've all learned within av
for quite some time now but essentially what we
do as activists is we find ourselves saying we
we with non-vegans all the time why do we do this
to animals you know we grow up i know that we're
trying to relate to non-vegans but it does take
away from individual accountability and people do
need to understand the clear difference between
veganism and non-veganism and they will not see
and understand that difference clearly enough
if you keep using language that isn't accurately
describing the issue if you keep saying we you're
not actually being accurate so be careful about
what it is you're saying when you tell non-vegans
that we as a society are responsible for animal
cruelty in farms it takes away the imperative
for individual accountability it makes them
think of lobbying or government programs instead
of personal responsibilities people need to feel
guilty to change they'll only change once they
understand that there is a difference between you
the vegan and them the non-vegan i understand that
that last slide might seem like we are creating
division between us and individuals it's not about
being deliberately combative and creating division
with people it's again just about making sure that
they understand clearly that there is a massive
difference between veganism and non-veganism
and i think you all already know this because
otherwise you wouldn't be vegan and you wouldn't
stay vegan and you understand that there is a
big difference between what you're doing now and
going back to being non-vegan a huge difference
and that's why we should really be careful
about the language we use okay why versus how
people already know how to go vegan it's really
simple stuff with the constant availability of
google and the internet anybody can figure out
how to become vegan instantly in order for people
to feel the need to become vegan they need to
be held accountable for why they should do it
with any other injustice you would never focus
on how by talking about how to not participate
in the violence focusing on the how in the context
of any other injustice would be an insult to the
victims and the entire movement fighting to
end their oppression part of me it's not to
say that how is not an important talking point we
should give people that but it's only at the very
end once we have sufficiently and emphatically
address the why factor you know we give people
a card as you know at the end we always arm
people with the resources and the how factor
all you really need as a compass to be vegan is
is what i'm doing right now vegan or not does this
restaurant have vegan meals is this product vegan
is this ingredient vegan is going to zoos vegan
okay so it's really simple really really simple
stuff and i think that you should be aware of
whether you're coddling people into this or
not and babying people into this is a problem
it shows weakness in the actual
message if you're doing that
vegetarianism is cancer to animal rights i'm not
just saying this for shock value i truly mean this
the longer the vegetarianism and veganism
get conflated the longer it will take
for us to get the message out there that
veganism is about non-human animal rights
and that that is a serious injustice that
people need to take very very seriously
vegetarians are non-vegans and should be
outreached in the same manner as anyone else
and in most cases even harder vegetarians are our
target market they're no different to paleo eaters
people who eat a paleo diet why should we treat
them any differently so as you may know people who
eat a paleo diet do not eat dairy and we as vegans
i use this point a lot and i hear other vegans
using this point a lot we talk about how the
dairy industry is quite possibly the cruelest
industry at least for land animals on earth
paleo eaters don't consume any dairy products
why are they any different to
vegetarians vegetarians don't consume
flesh while flesh is an obvious form of cruelty
we know as vegans that dairy is no different
and that what happens on dairy farms and in
slaughterhouses to the cows and their babies
is nothing short of an atrocity of a holocaust
and is no different to what happens to animals
in the meat industry arguably it's worse than
the dairy industry and so as you can imagine it
would be insane for us to call paleo people our
allies to put them in the same bracket as vegans
so why are we doing this with vegetarians it
makes absolutely no sense it's counterproductive
and it absolutely will marginalize the
seriousness of this injustice the longer
that we make vegetarians feel like they are animal
people like they are defenders of animals like
they are on the side of animal rights they need
to be held to account just like everybody else
okay so they are not allies don't let other vegans
or non-vegans manipulate you into thinking that
they are so when you start the conversation you
could say would you like to know why we're here
what's up guys how you doing man i'm doing really
well you wanna hear what we're doing oh sure
cool and with the context of the footage playing
tell them what the cube of truth sets out to do
what we are here doing is showing the reality
of what happens to animals in the meat dairy and
egg industries and also other industries
that exploit animals everything you see
here is standard practice here and around the
world what we're showing on these screens is
the standard practice for what happens in the meat
industry in this country but also around the world
these are the farms and the slaughterhouses
that label themselves free range grass fed
cage free organic ask the following open-ended
question what are your feelings on animal abuse
then confirm their stance to form moral
consistency with something like so is it
safe to say that you are against animal
abuse how does the footage make you feel
it makes you feel bad are you both against animal
abuse yes by the way most people will say yes
it's very rare that you'll get
anybody that says no to that question
ask them do you think it's possible to be
against animal abuse while demanding products
like meat dairy and eggs do you think
it's possible to be against animal abuse
while eating meat dairy or eggs and this is where
the truth starts to set in and most people say
that's a really good question or their objections
start to come out ask them what is stopping them
from not abusing animals and becoming vegan what
do you feel like would be stopping you and this
is important that you say what do you feel like
would be stopping you not what is stopping you
because there as you know nothing there is nothing
stopping anybody from going vegan really if you
live in a modern society what do you feel like
would be stopping you from not abusing animals
and being vegan it's also important
that you mention not abusing animals
and being vegan and not just saying what do you
feel like would be stopping you from being vegan
what do you feel like for you two as individuals
what do you feel like is holding you back from
not being responsible for any of this animal
abuse and living vegan it's much more powerful
to add in the fact that you're not abusing
animals when you're not vegan this will lead
to their objections objection handling whenever
a bystander brings up an objection place them
in the victim's position and allow them to
analyze the objection from that perspective
every single time this happens the objection
will fall apart you know as long as they're being
genuine they're not being disingenuous
intellectually no matter what the objection is
it always crumbles i'm still gonna make meat but
i'm gonna try and do it as humane as i can imagine
yourself in the animal's position how do i murder
you humanely is there a humane way for him to be
murdered i'm asking you now just so you can help
out maybe there isn't is there why do you say that
yeah he's not consenting to being killed is he
he's not saying yes i'm okay with being killed you
wouldn't say that would you most objections are
easy and quick to respond to some are more nuanced
and require a deeper explanation but they should
still be quick to respond to your response should
always anchor back to individual accountability
it should always end up with the bystander you're
speaking with being in the hot seat if it doesn't
end up with that bystander being in the hot seat
you aren't anchoring that point that you've
just made correctly it has to always end there
bring it back to the individual if they try to
create excuses that try to remove accountability
for example pointing to rural communities
lions low income families etc don't get lost
in lengthy explanations again these things are
distractions bring it back to the individual
by placing themselves in the victim's position and
asking how that excuse justifies their personal
responsibility to animal abuse i need to
update these slides to be completely honest
contribution and support aren't
the correct words to use here
people aren't merely contributing to the animal
holocaust they're literally responsible for it
i'm going to give you an example if
a hunter's wife is at home and before
the hunter goes out to have a day of hunting
the wife says have a great day hunting honey
she's supporting hunting but she's not
actually shooting the animals herself
non-vegans aren't merely doing that non-vegans
are quite literally responsible for the shooting
for the enslavement for the torture and the
murder so contribution and support are not
accurate words to be using here responsibility
is the word to replace those words in all cases
tie in the benefit tie into benefit
only once they concede by saying
if they're against animal abuse
then it's not possible to be against
animal abuse while being responsible for
it the number one benefit for being vegan
the benefit is that they no longer have
to be tortured and abused because of you
in other words you no longer have to be the reason
that animals suffer in the worst unimaginable ways
for you as an individual if you say
that you're against animal abuse
and what you see on the screens then when you're
vegan you no longer have to be a hypocrite
now this is the part of the
interaction where things get very real
and where the person understands that you're not
just having a wishy-washy you're not just verbally
leafleting you're not just saying what vegans
tend to say you're having a real conversation
about a real issue here and you're calling
them out but you're not doing it because you
are trying to be an [ __ ] you also should
understand that telling somebody the truth is
the most compassionate thing that you can do it's
the most kind and loving thing that you can do
sometimes the truth can be harsh and can
sound brutal but you have to understand
that that's just the nature of truth the
truth is not always a bowl of cherries
and when you're a medium of truth you have
to accept that as part of your responsibility
when you're spreading the truth you have to
be comfortable with the fact that sometimes
it will sound brutal but you're not saying
it from a malicious place your intention
is to end animal abuse and to change the actions
of humans so that they are no longer responsible
for it in a way it's liberating for the human as
well as the animal who they are responsible for
oppressing so do you know what the number one
benefit is for being vegan can you take a guess
yeah what do you think it is that as well yeah
yeah maybe it will help um like the industry
to not like produce as much yeah because you're
no longer demanding yeah and they are supplying
demand that's basic economics you're one less
person who's demanding it yeah let me put it
to you this way also the number one benefit for
the animals is that they're no longer tormented
abused and harmed in any way because of you
you're no longer the reason that animals
suffer immensely are tormented and murdered
the benefit for you as individuals also
is that when you say you're against animal
abuse you'll no longer be hypocrites
do you disagree with that does that does that
sound fair to you does that make sense to you
yeah this drives home the accountability and makes
them understand the consequences of their choices
so this is where you close the conversation always
end every outreach conversation by asking what the
individual will be personally doing to
take action ask the open-ended question
after our conversation what are you
going to do about this injustice
after a long conversation they may they may
still say that they'll only reduce or do nothing
or they may say something like i'll try to do
better if you can sense that the interaction will
keep going in circles end the conversation with
the statement but with people who say i'm going
to try to do better or i'll reduce how much meat i
eat they are still not getting how serious this is
do you deem this to be an injustice
and usually they will say yes i do
and then i say would you take the stance that you
just took with any other injustice you know if we
were talking about yourself as the victim in this
injustice would you find it acceptable for your
oppressor to say that they are going to try to
stop oppressing you or would you only deem it
acceptable for them to stop immediately so
what do you think you'll do about this then
eat less medium yeah maybe even stop eventually
okay now is what you're seeing on the screens
is animal abuse and injustice to each of you
yes yes yeah okay would you take the position
that you just took with any other injustice
let's say you're the victims in this scenario
would you find it acceptable for your oppressor
to try to harm you less and to do less harming
of you or would you want them to stop entirely
immediately so please don't compromise
when it comes to these non-human animals
because they suffer just like you would if you
were in their position again they may not like
the sound of that um that it may not be what they
want to hear because essentially what they're
doing when they say i'm going to try or reduce
is they're pandering to you because they want
to tell you what you want to hear they can see
that they're in they're on the wrong side of this
that's why they're saying these things to
you to end the conversation you you become a
mirror at that point for the ugliness that they
represent and when you say that their stance is
not acceptable regardless of what they say after
that you've put the needle where it needs to be
an effective statement in this situation can be
and this is the last line that we always give
people we tend to leave them with this so keep in
mind that for however long that you're not vegan
animals will be abused and tortured because of you
so when you're ready to stop abusing animals and
align your actions with your words you know what
to do think about what side of history you want to
stand on what i'd leave you guys with is just keep
in mind that for however long you're not vegan
unfortunately you guys are going to be
responsible for what's taking place on
the screen this animal abuse so just think
about and decide what side of history you
guys want to stand on when it comes to stamping
out this injustice and that's the workshop guys